

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Chicago, IL USA

□ (224) 258-2804 | Scontact@rasheedsaad.com | www.rasheedsaad.com | srashee

Summary_

I'm currently a Software Artisan at Accenture writing software for business products. I'm passionate about building, tinkering and making things better. I have experience developing on embedded systems and cloud technologies. I'm also attending University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign for Computer Science.

Work Experience _____

Accenture Industry X

SOFTWARE ARTISAN

Apr 2021 - Present

Scaled out a Smart City data ingestion pipeline named UrbanOS using AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes and Helm.

Motorola Solutions Secure Products Group

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

- Built Software for next generation Radio's in C.
- Built Software for encryption systems in C and Python.
- Developed encryption software and security-related features for multiple embedded products.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I

- Implemented testing framework using IP Stack and TCP/UDP Protocols.
- Implemented cross-platform applications for a variety of different host architectures.
- Integrated legacy code base with modern continuous integration and deployment tools.

Education

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, Illinois

M.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2019 - Present

 Relevant Courses: Distributed Systems (Cloud Computing), Parallel Programming, Theory and Practice of Data Cleaning and Text Information Systems.

Northern Illinois University

Dekalb, Illinois

B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015 - 2017

- · Distinction: Cum Laude
- Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms, UNIX, Networking, Databases, iOS Mobile Programming, Assembler Mainframe, Java, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture and Systems

Skills_

- Languages: C, C++, Python, Swift, Javascript, Haskell, Java, and Scripting(Shell, PS1, Batch)
- **Tools:** Git, Docker, GDB, ARM debugger, Clearcase, Jenkins, Github Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Artifactory, Conan, CMake, EKS, and EC2
- Reference: AWS, Azure, Windows, Linux, ARM, and RHEL
- **Embedded:** GPIO, USB, Serial, RS232, and SPI Interfaces
- **Security:** Experience working with encryption algorithms, key management and general understanding of web security

Projects_

Causal Data Mining

CS410: Text Information Systems

ITERATIVE TOPIC MODELING WITH TIME SERIES FEEDBACK

October 2020

- · Worked with a team to develop a system in Python to analyze historical data and build graphical associations with historical events.
- The project and code is an open-sourced research project available for viewing here.

Google Extension Google Chrome Store

MINIMALIST Feb. 2019 - Present

• Developed and maintain a minimal note taking application for Google Chrome.

• Available for download in the Google Chrome Store.

ACM WCS Mentorship Program

MENTOR

University of Illinois at UC

May. 2020

• Mentored an Ungraduate Computer Science student.

• Met virtually on a regular cadence to help matriculation during the COVID 19 Pandemic.

Motorola YPG SCH Motorola Solutions

SOCIAL BRANCH LEAD

Jan. 2020 - Apr 2021

· Led a team to setup events for Motorola social events.

- Event planning for virtual events during the pandemic.
- Event planning for social in-person events for 500 attendants.

Motorola Hackathon Schaumburg, Illinois

TECHNICAL ENABLEMENT LEAD

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- · Led a team to setup required technical infrastructure for hackathon, hosting approximately 100 participants.
- Team enabled participants to use GitLab, GitHub, Cloud Instances alongside proprietary Motorola hardware.

iOS Application Northern Illinois University

UniBoard Dec. 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Developed a social media iOS application in Swift 3 that allowed university students to sign up and communicate publicly through posts and images.
- Used Firebase for the back-end and data store to allow users to comment and like other user's posts.